Albert C. Peale Papers Mss.SMs.Coll.5
American Philosophical Society
Albert C. Peale Papers
Bulk, 1869-1910
1842-1913
Mss.SMs.Coll.5
American Philosophical Society
2.5 Linear feet 5 boxes
Albert Charles Peale (1849-1913), the great-grandson of Charles Willson Peale (1741-1827), was a geologist for the United States Geological Survey (USGS) and its predecessor agency, a member of the Ferdinand Hayden expeditions that explored and mapped the western United States, an author in geology, mineralogy, and paleobotany, and an aide at the United States National Museum (today the Smithsonian Institution's National Museum of Natural History). Edwin Roger Kirk (1884-1955) corresponded with Frank Springer about crinoids; assisted Edward Ulrich in studying sediments of the Appalachians; surveyed the Rocky Mountains, the Great Basin, and southeastern Alaska as a USGS paleontologist; and collected the papers of Peale and other geologists. Peale’s correspondence (1868-1912, bulk 1870s-80s) relate to various federal geological expeditions. Letters between Peale and William Rush Taggart, the largest single portion of the series, focus on matters of congressional funding. Kirk’s series (1900-09) contains the correspondence of Kirk and other geologists; most frequent are letters from Frank Springer to Kirk relating to rock formations. The collection also contains several diaries and sketchbooks from Peale (bulk 1872-77), including those kept during the Hayden expeditions, correspondence relating to the Geological Survey of Kentucky (1888-1893), and miscellaneous letters and memorabilia (c. 1820s-1940s), often relating to the Peale family.
Peale, A. C. (Albert Charles), 1849-1914
Related Archival Materials note
APS holds several additional collections relating to the Peale family; see especially the Titian Ramsey Peale Sketches (1817-1875) for biographical data and materials relating to Albert Charles Peale’s great-uncle, who participated in the Long Expedition to the Rocky Mountains (1819-21) and the Wilkes Expedition to the Pacific Coast, Fiji, and the Philippines (1838-42).
The United States Geological Survey Field Records Library in Denver holds many notebooks and field notes created by Albert Charles Peale (1873-1907, n.d.) in his service for that agency.
The Smithsonian Institution Archives in Washington, D.C., holds the Edwin Kirk Papers (1783-1893, 1905-1941, n.d.).
The University of Wyoming American Heritage Center in Laramie, Wyoming, holds the William Rush Taggart Papers (1872-1873, .45 cubic feet).
Scope and Contents note
Series I consists of Albert C. Peale’s correspondence, spanning from 1868 to 1912 (mostly 1870s-80s) and primarily relates to various federal geological expeditions. His most frequent correspondents include colleagues William Rush Taggart and Charles Richmond, and eventual wife Emilie Wiswell. Letters between Peale and Taggart, the largest single portion of the series, focus on matters of congressional funding for expeditions.
William Rush Taggart, assistant geologist and lawyer, was born on September 4, 1849, in Smithville, Ohio. He obtained a bachelor’s degree from the University of Wooster (Ohio) in 1871. After teaching for a year in Wooster High School, he received an appointment with the United States Geological and Geographical Survey of the Territories in the spring of 1872.
He met and befriended his peer Peale sometime before January 1872, the date of his first letter in the collection. From 1872 to 1873, Taggart served as an assistant of geologist Frank H. Bradley (“Prof. B.” in his letters) on the Hayden expedition to Jackson Hole, Wyoming Territory. The present-day Taggart Lake, in Grand Teton National Park, is named for him.
Taggart returned to Wooster to study law in the office of Charles M. Yocum, then obtained a law degree from the University of Michigan in 1875. After practicing law with Yocum for six months, Taggart was hired as an assistant and stenographer for the solicitor of the Pennsylvania Company in Salem, Ohio. He succeeded as solicitor two years later. During this time, he frequently corresponded with Peale and collected photographs and artifacts from his friend’s expeditions. Taggart married Margaret Waterworth (d. 1916) on September 13, 1877.
He later joined the law firm of Dillon and Swain in New York City (1887-91), with clients such as the Pennsylvania Company, Western Union Telegraph Company, and several railroads (1891-1911). He ultimately became vice president and general counsel for Western Union and a director for American Telegraph and Cable Company (1911-22). Taggart died on September 28, 1922, at his summer home in New Canaan, Connecticut, of complications from bronchitis.
Charles Richmond, ornithologist and museum curator, was born in Kenosha, Wisconsin, in 1868. Shortly after his mother’s death in 1880, he moved with his family to Washington, D.C., where Smithsonian bird curator Robert Ridgway mentored his early ornithological interest. Richmond left school to become a messenger for the USGS in 1885. In 1888, he collected birds on a USGS expedition to Montana. He also accompanied his brother and three friends on a horticultural and ornithological expedition to Nicaragua and Costa Rica in 1892-93, donating the resulting bird specimens to the United States National Museum. He obtained employment at the museum for most of the remainder of his life, serving as night watchman (1893-94), assistant curator of birds (1894-1918), and associate curator of birds (1918-32). He married Louise H. Seville in 1898, and died in Washington, D.C., in 1932.
Series II spans from 1900 to 1909 and contains the correspondence of Edwin Kirk and other geologists; most numerous are letters from Frank Springer to Kirk relating mostly to rock formations. Charles Wachsmuth is another common correspondent with both Kirk and Springer. The second series also includes some correspondence of Edward Oscar Ulrich relating to the Geological Survey of Kentucky (1888-1893).
Frank Springer, paleontologist, was born in 1848 in Wapello, Iowa. He attended law school at the University of Iowa and was admitted to the bar in 1869. He married Josephine M. Bishop in 1876. Perhaps influenced by fellow Iowa attorney Charles Wachsmuth, Springer developed an interest in paleontology and wrote the Revision of the Palæocrinoidea between 1879 and 1886, published by Philadelphia’s Academy of Natural Sciences; the first of many such studies he would author. He later served as regent of the Museum of New Mexico, and died in East Las Vegas, New Mexico, in 1927.
Edward Oscar Ulrich, geologist, was born in 1857 in Cincinnati, and grew up mostly in Covington, Kentucky. He joined the Cincinnati Society of Natural History in 1877, serving as their curator of paleontology from 1878-79. After two years as superintendent of a silver and lead prospect in Boulder, Colorado, Ulrich returned to Kentucky. Between 1882 and 1884 he wrote and illustrated six papers on fossil bryozoans, and soon after received contracts to do similar work for the Illinois Geological Survey (published 1890) and the Minnesota Geological and Natural History Survey (published 1895). He also attained a temporary position with the USGS in 1897. He moved to Washington, D.C., upon becoming a permanent USGS geologist in 1901. He continued to publish geological works and do field surveys in the Mississippi Valley, the Appalachians, and other states, retiring in 1932. He died in 1944 in Washington.
Charles Wachsmuth, paleontologist and lawyer, was born in 1829 in Hanover, Germany. After an early career as a lawyer, Wachsmuth emigrated to the United States and settled in Burlington, Iowa. He developed an interest in the area’s crinoid fossils, and traveled to Europe to study fossils in the British Museum in the 1865. Upon returning, he collected fossils to send to the museum and collaborated with Frank Springer to publish several studies on crinoids. Wachsmuth died in 1896.
Series III contains miscellaneous letters and memorabilia (c. 1820s-1940s) of the Peale family. These include poems written by Albert, items from Albert’s great-uncle Titian Ramsay Peale, a sketch of a Kentucky warbler sent to Charles Willson Peale (either Albert’s father or his illustrious great-grandfather) from Ohio, postcards, photographs, and a lock of hair from Rachel Brewer Peale (Albert's great-grandmother).
Series IV is made up of bound volumes from A. C. Peale or his mother Harriet Peale. From Albert, seven diaries (the earliest c. 1865-69, the other six 1872-77), one daybook covering a teenage Albert's observations of weather and Civil War military drills (1864), two university lecture notebooks (c. 1868-70), and one undated sketchbook. From Harriet, a receipt (recipe) book, mostly undated but containing a pamphlet from 1878.
The first diary is undated but covers A. C. Peale's visit to Washington, D.C., sometime during President Andrew Johnson's administration (1865-69). The remaining diaries cover various western expeditions in which Peale participated, mostly in the present states of Colorado, Wyoming, and Utah. The diary from May-August 1873 (to the creeks of Castle Peek) includes several notable references to expedition photographer William Henry Jackson. The final diary (1877, to western Wyoming) especially contains many accounts of interactions with Shosoni Indians and also encounters with Bannacks; the diary from July-November 1874 (to the branches of the Gunnison River) also contain references to nearby Indian inhabitants.
Edwin Kirk assembled Peale’s papers, then leaving them and his own papers to his wife Page upon his death. They passed to the Kirks’ daughter and granddaughter before the latter donated them to the American Philosophical Society in 2007.
Biographical/Historical note
Albert Charles Peale, geologist, mineralogist, and paleobotanist, was born April 1, 1849, in Heckscherville, Pennsylvania, the son of Charles Willson Peale (1821-1871) and Harriet Friel. His father was the namesake of Albert's great-grandfather, painter and museum proprietor Charles Willson Peale (1741-1827). Albert's grandfather was Rubens Peale (1784-1865); his great-uncles included portraitist Rembrandt Peale (1778-1840) and artist, naturalist, and early photographer Titian Ramsay Peale (1799-1885). Albert had one sibling, a sister named Clara Elizabeth (b. 1851).
Peale attended Central High School in Philadelphia, obtaining a bachelor's degree in 1868 and a master's in 1873, and finished medical school at the University of Pennsylvania in 1871. From 1871 to 1879, Peale served as a mineralogist and geologist for the United States Geological and Geographic Survey of the Territories. As such, he traveled on several of the Ferdinand Hayden expeditions that explored and mapped the western United States. In 1875 he married Emilie Wiswell, the daughter of the Rev. George F. Wiswell (1820-1892), a Philadelphia minister and former president of Delaware College (today the University of Delaware).
In 1882, Peale wrote Yellowstone National Park and Thermal Springs, a landmark survey of the nation's first national park. The following year, he became a geologist with the United States Geological Survey (USGS), a post he held until 1898. While employed there, he wrote several other notable works: Mineral Springs of the United States (1886), The Classification of American Mineral Waters (1887), and The Natural Mineral Waters of the United States (1895).
In 1898, Peale joined the staff of the United States National Museum (today the Smithsonian Institution's National Museum of Natural History), as a paleobotanist, a role he served in until his death. He wrote two other notable scientific works, Classification of Mineral Waters (1902) and The Stratigraphic Position and Age of the Judith River Formation (1913), as well as a work of family history, Biographical Sketches of Charles Willson Peale and of Titian R. Peale (1905). Peale died in 1913 in Washington, D.C.
While at the National Museum, one of Peale's proteges was Edwin Roger Kirk (1884-1955). Born December 6, 1884, in Richland, South Dakota, the son of Nathan and Caroline Kirk, Edwin's's interest in geology began early, as he was already corresponding with Frank Springer about crinoids at the age of fifteen. He obtained his bachelor’s degree from Columbia University in 1907, and served as an assistant paleontologist at the university until 1909 (he would later earn a doctorate there). That year he entered federal service as a junior geologist with the USGS, assisting Edward Oscar Ulrich in studying Ordovician and Silurian sediments of the Appalachians. (USGS operated out of the United States National Museum at the time, Kirk when Kirk would have met A. C. Peale.)
Kirk became a paleontologist with USGS in 1914, and conducted field trips to the Rocky Mountains, the Great Basin, and southeastern Alaska. He married sometime prior to his 1918 World War I draft registration; his wife was named Page. In 1920, he left USGS to work as a paleontologist for the Bolivia-Argentina Exploration Corporation.
He returned to USGS in 1921 and remained there for the rest of his career as an associate geologist (1921-52) and geologist (1952-54). He assembled Peale’s papers sometime before his death in 1955. Peale and Kirk’s papers then passed to Page Kirk, then to the Kirks’ daughter and granddaughter before the latter donated them to the American Philosophical Society in 2007.
References
Not including APS accession records and finding aids, biographical dictionaries, or encyclopedias.
Massa, William R., Jr., and William Cox. “Record Unit 7245: Edwin Kirk Papers, 1783-1893, 1905-1941 and undated.” Smithsonian Institution Archives, 2003, http://siarchives.si.edu/findingaids/FARU7245.htm (9 April 2009).
“Presidential Objectives Project: George Franklin Wiswell.” University of Delaware Archives, 2004, http://www.udel.edu/csg/PresWeb/bios/Wiswell.doc (9 April 2009).
Randall, Emilius O., and Daniel J. Ryan. “William Rush Taggart.” History of Ohio: The Rise and Progress of an American State, Vol. 6. New York: Century History Company, 1915. 155-157.
“Rush Taggart dies at his summer home.” New York Times 29 September 1922, 15 (New York Times Article Archive).
Sellers, Charles Coleman. Charles Willson Peale. Vol. 2. Philadelphia: American Philosophical Society, 1947.
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
Gift of Elizabeth Moyer and Michael Powanda, 2007 and 2008.
Hayden, F. V., (Ferdinand Vandeveer), 1829-1887; Kirk, Edwin, 1884-1955; Peale family; Springer, Frank; Taggart, William Rush, 1849-1922; Ulrich, E.O. (Edward Oscar), 1857-1944; Geological surveys -- United States.; Geological surveys --Yellowstone National Park; Geologists.; Geology--Kentucky; Mineralogy - Research - United States
- Correspondence, Albert Peale and Family, 1842-1915
  - Peale, W. B. to C. W. Peale and Mother, 1837 Jan. 22; 4.0 p.
  - Schroeder, J.F. to A.C. Peale, 1842 Nov 4; 3.0 p.
  - Peale, T. R. to unidentified, 1868 April 29; 1.0 p.
  - Haverstick, A. C. to A. C. Peale, 1868 July 21; 4.0 p.
  - Weaver, W. to A. C. Peale, 1868 Aug. 13; 2.0 p.
  - Haverstick, A. C to A. C. Peale, 1868 Aug. 29; 2.0 p.
  - Haverstick, A.C. to A.C. Peale, 1869 May 16; 4.0 p.
  - Unknown to A.C. Peale, 1869 May 12; 4.0 p.
  - Wheatley, C. M. to C. W. Peale, 1869 March 1; 2.0 p.
  - C.S.T. to A. C. Peale, 1869 July; 3.0 p.
  - Unknown to A. C. Peale, 1870 Aug. 4; 2.0 p.
  - Gannett to A. C. Peale, 1870(?) Dec. 30; 1.0 p.
  - Dixon, George B. to A. C. Peale, 1871 Jan. 16; 2.0 p.
  - Dixon, George B. to A. C. Peale, 1871 May 5; 3.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1871 May 28.; 6.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1871 July 4; 4.0 p.
  - Gower, J. J. to A. C. Peale, 1871 Dec. 2; 1.0 p.
  - Smith, Alfred to A. C. Peale, 1871 Dec. 18; 2.0 p.
  - Duncan, J. W. to A. C. Peale, 1872 Jan. 7; 2.0 p.
  - Allen, George N. to A. C. Peale, 1872 Jan. 11; 4.0 p.
  - Taggart, William Rush to A. C. Peale, 1872 Jan. 21; 2.0 p.
  - Jackson, W. H. to A. C. Peale, 1872 Feb. 18; 2.0 p.
  - Brown, Alexander E. to A. C. Peale, 1872 Jan. 26; 4.0 p.
  - Trumbull, Charles S. to A. C. Peale, 1872 Mar. 11; 1.0 p.
  - Sellers, Charles, Jr. to A. C. Peale, 1872 Mar. 23; 2.0 p.
  - Abbott, Lawrence(?) to A. C. Peale, 1872 Apr. 9; 1.0 p.
  - Hawkins & Wade to A. C. Peale, 1872 April 11; 2.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1872 July 9; 8.0 p.
  - American Tract Society to A. C. Peale, 1872 Dec. 7; 2.0 p.
  - Hovey, Stephen D. to A. C. Peale, 1873 Jan. 1; 2.0 p.
  - Trumbull, Charles to A. C. Peale, 1873 Jan. 23; 2.0 p.
  - Platt, Walter B. to A. C. Peale, 1873 Feb. 4; 2.0 p.
  - (Blakefield, E.?) to A. C. Peale, 1873 Feb. 17; 1.0 p.
  - Sloane, T. O’C. to A. C. Peale, 1873 March 2; 2.0 p.
  - Sloane, T. O'C. to A. C. Peale, 1873 Mar. 11; 4.0 p.
  - Cox, Frank to A. C. Peale, 1873 Mar. 27; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, William R. to A. C. Peale, 1873 Mar. 28; 2.0 p.
  - Trautwine, John to A. C. Peale, 1873 Apr. 28; 1.0 p.
  - Abbott, Lyman to A. C. Peale, 1873 May 7; 2.0 p.
  - McCloud (?) to A. C. Peale, 1873 May 9; 2.0 p.
  - Peale, A.C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1873 June 29; 4.0 p.
  - Hovey, S.D. to A. C. Peale, 1873 July 1; 1.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1873 July 5; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A.C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1873 July 8; 4.0 p.
  - Hovey, S. D. to A. C. Peale, 1873 July 11; 2.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1873 July 12; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A.C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1873 July 18; 2.0 p.
  - Wiswell, E (?) to A. C. Peale (?), 1873 (?) July 28; 2.0 p.
  - Peale, A.C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1873 Aug 17; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A.C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1873 Aug 23; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1873 Aug. 31; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1873 Sept. 7; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1873 Sept. 16; 4.0 p.
  - Turnbull, C. S. to A. C. Peale, 1873 Oct. 8; 4.0 p.
  - Stuckle, H. M (?). to A. C. Peale, 1873 Nov. 3; 2.0 p.
  - Stevenson, J. to A. C. Peale, 1873 Nov 4; 1.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1873 Nov. 13; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1873 Nov. 24; 2.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1873 Nov. 25; 10.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1873 Dec. 7; 4.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1873 Dec. 10; 1.0 p.
  - Abbott, L. to A. C. Peale (?), 1873 Dec 11; 1.0 p.
  - Stuckle, H. M (?). to A. C. Peale, 1873 Dec 16; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1874 Jan. 5; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1874 Jan. 20; 3.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1874 Jan. 27; 1.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1874 Feb. 10; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1874 March 9; 1.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1874 March 10; 3.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C.Peale, 1874 March 20; 2.0 p.
  - Stuckle, H. W. to A. C. Peale, 1874 April 10; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1874 April 14; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1874 April 27; 4.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1874 May 14; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1874 June 7; 4.0 p.
  - Stevenson, J. to A. C. Peale, 1874 June 30; 1.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1874 July 2; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1874 July 12; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A.C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1874 Aug 13; 4.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1874 Aug 24; 4.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1874 Nov. 8; 4.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1874 Dec 13; 4.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1875 Jan 24; 4.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1875 Feb 8; 3.0 p.
  - Kellogg(?), Frank W. to A. C. Peale, 1875 March 4; 4.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R. to A. C. Peale, 1875 March 21; 3.0 p.
  - Porter, Judge to A. C. Peale, 1875 April 16; 2.0 p.
  - Porter, Judge to A.C. Peale, 1875 April 16; 2.0 p.
  - Abbott, Lyman to A. C. Peale, 1875 April 17; 2.0 p.
  - Abbott, Lyman to A. C. Peale, 1875 April 17; 2.0 p.
  - Abbott, Lyman to A. C. Peale, 1875 April 27; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1875 April 28; 3.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1875 May 10; 3.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1875 June 4; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1875 June 6; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1875 June 9; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1875 June 12; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1875 June 17; 6.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1875 June 22; 2.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1875 June 23; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A.C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1875 June 28; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1875 July 2; 4.0 p.
  - Unknown to A. C. Peale, 1875 July 11; 4.0 p.
  - Turnbull, C.S. to A. C. Peale, 1875 July 16; 2.0 p.
  - Peale, A.C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1875 Aug 1; 4.0 p.
  - Peale, A.C. to Emilie Wiswell, 1875 Aug 6; 4.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1875 Sept. 9; 6.0 p.
  - Endlich to A. C. Peale, 1875 Oct. 20; 1.0 p.
  - Chittenden to A. C. Peale, 1875 Oct. 30; 2.0 p.
  - Henry, Joseph to A.C. Peale, 1875 Nov 2; 1.0 p.
  - Porter, Judge to A. C. Peale, 1875 Nov. 10; 3.0 p.
  - Henry, Joseph to A. C. Peale, 1875 Dec. 1; 1.0 p.
  - Chittenden to A. C. Peale, 1876 Jan. 4; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1876 Jan. 30; 2.0 p.
  - Coulter, John M. to A. C. Peale, 1876 Feb. 4; 3.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1876 Feb. 7; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1876 Feb. 10; 1.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1876 Feb. 21; 1.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1876 Feb. 24; 3.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1876 March 6; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1876 March 16; 2.0 p.
  - Williams, Henry T. to A. C. Peale, 1876 March 23; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1876 March 27; 2.0 p.
  - Abbott, Lyman to A. C. Peale, 1876 May 5; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1876 June 9; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1876 Oct. 14; 2.0 p.
  - Endlich to A. C. Peale, 1876 Nov. 14; 1.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1876 Nov. 30; 2.0 p.
  - Atkinson, W.R. to A. C. Peale, 1877 Feb. 24; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1877 April 4; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1877 April 11; 4.0 p.
  - Atkinson, W.R. to A. C. Peale + map, 1877 July 15; 3.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1877 Oct. 29; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1877 Nov. 17; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1877 Dec. 15; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W.R to A. C. Peale, 1878 Feb. 21; 2.0 p.
  - Goode, G. Brown to A. C. Peale, 1878 April 2; 1.0 p.
  - Aldrich, Chris(?) to A. C. Peale, 1878 April 9; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1878 April 15; 2.0 p.
  - Stoddard(?), O.N. to A. C. Peale, 1878 May 4; 3.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1878 May 16; 2.0 p.
  - Aldrich, Chris(?) to A. C. Peale, 1878 May 22; 1.0 p.
  - Stevenson, J. to A. C. Peale, 1878 May 26; 1.0 p.
  - Pearson to A. C. Peale, 1878 June 14; 1.0 p.
  - Aldrich, Chris(?) to A. C. Peale, 1878 July 24; 4.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1878 July 29; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1878 Nov. 24; 1.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1879 Jan. 4; 2.0 p.
  - Juliette to Mrs. Peale, 1879(?) March 22; 2.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1879 April 19; 2.0 p.
  - Mack, David to A. C. Peale, 1879 June 8; 2.0 p.
  - Hassler, Emma to Mrs. Peale, 1879 July 11; 4.0 p.
  - Taggart, W. R. to A. C. Peale, 1879 Aug. 19; 2.0 p.
  - Campbell, W. to A.C. Peale, 1886 Nov 3; 2.0 p.
  - Johnson, J. O. to A. C. Peale, 1887 Jan 22; 4.0 p.
  - Van Bibber, W.C., M.D. to A. C. Peale, 1887 June 21; 3.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Charles Richmond, 1887 July 2; 1.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Charles Richmond, 1887 July 13; 2.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Charles Richmond, 1887 July 15; 1.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Charles Richmond, 1887 July 19; 1.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Charles Richmond, 1887 Aug. 1; 1.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Charles Richmond, 1887 Aug. 7; 1.0 p.
  - Peale, A. C. to Charles Richmond, 1887 Aug. 9; 1.0 p.